aoi hoshi ni senritsu ga hashiru
a
o
i
ho
shi
ni
se
n
ri
tsu
ga
ha
shi
ru
A shudder runs over the blue planet
푸른 지구에 전율이 흐른다
kuroi arashi chikazuku toki
ku
ro
i
a
ra
shi
chi
ka
zu
ku
to
ki
It's the time the dark storm approaches
검은 폭풍이 닥쳐오는 순간
kokoro no oku de mezameru HERO
ko
ro
no
o
ku
de
me
za
ru
HE
RO
It's as if a hero is awakening on the inside
마음 속의 눈을 뜬 영웅들이여
tobitatsu no da furimukazu ni
to
bi
ta
tsu
no
da
fu
ri
mu
ka
zu
ni
Fly away and don't look back!
뒤돌아보지 말고 날아가라
DAGWON kagayake DAGWON
DA
G
WON
ka
ga
ya
ke
DA
G
WON
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Brave Command Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Dagwon... Shine on!! Dagwon!
다그온 빛나라!! 다그온
heiwa mamoru namae sa
he
i
wa
ma
mo
ru
na
ma
e
sa
The name that protects the peace
평화를 지키는 이름이다
DAGWON oretachi DAGWON
DA
G
WON
o
re
ta
chi
DA
G
WON
Dagwon! We are Dagwon!
다그온 우리는 다그온
yume wa zettai watasanai
yu
me
wa
ze
t
ta
i
wa
ta
sa
na
i
We will never hand over our dream
꿈은 절대로 넘겨줄 수 없다
afureru yuuki te ni shitai nara
a
fu
re
ru
yu
u
ki
te
ni
shi
ta
i
na
ra
To grab the overflowing courage
넘쳐흐르는 용기를 거머쥐고 싶다면
tsuyoku tsuyoku yuujou shinjiru koto sa
tsu
yo
ku
tsu
yo
ku
yu
u
jo
shi
n
ji
ru
ko
to
sa
We believe in our friendship firmly
우리 우정을 굳게 믿는 거다
kizutsuku koto mo osore wa shinai
ki
zu
tsu
ku
ko
to
mo
o
so
re
wa
shi
na
i
We are not afraid of getting hurt
상처입는 것도 두렵지 않아
mugendai no mirai wo egaku sono tame ni
mu
ge
n
da
i
no
mi
ra
i
wo
e
ga
ku
so
no
ta
me
ni
In order to reach that infinite future!
무한대의 미래를 그려내기 위해서라면
Brutal aliens escaped from the Space Prison Sargasso.
우주 감옥 사르갓소의 흉악한 우주인들
To protect the Earth from those evil hands, the brave high school students, Dagwon, keep fighting on to this day.
그 마수로부터 지구를 지키기 위해 오늘도 계속해서 싸우는 고등학생 용자 다그온
The result of their further power up is Dag Fire's Strength Fusion, Power Dagwon.
그들의 거듭되는 파워업이 바로 다그 파이어의 강력 합체 파워 다그온인 것이다
Electrostatic Appearance! Dag Thunder
전격 등장 다그 선더
Space Fish Man Sabarath Seijin
Appears
우주 어인 사바라스 성인
등장
-Spiritual phenomenon?
-Yes.
-심령현상?
-네
(Kinjirou/Sontoku Ninomiya: 19C Japanese agricultural leader)
It's a school closed long time ago, but they say every night, an image of Kinjirou Ninomiya wanders around the school.
꽤 오래전에 폐교된 학교인데요, 밤마다 니노미야 킨지로 상(像)이 교내를 돌아다닌대요
Kinjirou Ninomiya?
니노미야 킨지로?
(Manneken Pis: cupid-like statue urinating into a fountain)
No, is it actually Manneken Pis? Anyway, it's famous around that place.
아니, 그게… 오줌싸개 소년이었던가? 아니, 어쨌든, 그 주변에서는 쫙 소문이 나서요
It's kinda doubtful,  but well, I guess there's no harm in investigating.
좀 미심쩍은 이야기지만 뭐, 조사해 볼 가치는 있는 것 같네
That's our Ms. Maria! I thought you'd say so, so I brought some camping tools.
역시 마리아 씨야! 그렇게 나올 것 같아서 캠프 도구를 준비해 왔답니다
Fortunately today is Saturday...
다행히 오늘은 토요일고…
To explain, Geki just wants to be with Maria only by two.
쉽게 말해서, 게키는 누나랑 단 둘이 있고 싶어서…
Ms. Maria!
마리아 씨!
Why you-!
이런, 이자식!
Oh well...
정말…
You dropped this.
떨어뜨리셨어요
Thank you.
고마워요
You have a bizarre taste.
별난 취미군요
A rice straw doll?
볏짚 인형이라니…
W-wait up!
자, 잠깐 기다려요!
How did he know what was inside?
어떻게 종이 봉투 안의 물건을…
Why are you bringing that?
왜 그런 걸 가지고 돌아다니는 거야?
He is the one.
저 사람이야
That is the ideal person I need!
저 사람이야말로 내가 추구하던 이상의 인물!
Maria!
누나~
I guess my sister has opened her eyes for love.
우리 누나도 이제 간신히 사랑에 눈을 뜬 건가
Good morning.
안녕하십니까
Morning. I like your greeting full of vigor...
좋은 아침이다 기운 넘치는 인사라
매우 만족스럽다만…
...but who are you?
그런데 너는?
Rai Utsumi.
우츠미 라이
I moved schools as a new freshman of Sankai High School.
오늘 산카이 고등학교 1학년에 전학왔습니다
A transfer student, huh? I am the chief of disciplines-
전학생이군
난 풍기 위원장인…
Kai Hirose senpai, right?
히로세 카이 선배시죠?
(Senpai: an upperclassman or someone of a higher age)
How did you know my name?
내 이름을 알고 있나?
Morning, Kai.
안녕, 카이
Morning.
좋은 아침
Go- good morning!
아, 안녕하십니까
Shin Sawamura senpai, Yoku Kazamatsuri senpai!
사와무라 신 선배
카자마츠리 요쿠 선배
-You are...?
-Who is this guy?
-너는?
-요녀석 누구냐?
Actually, I had something important to tell you senpai-tachi...
네, 사실은 선배들께 중요한 이야기를…
I found you, you punk!
찾았다, 이놈아~
I got him, Ms. Maria!
잡았습니다, 마리아 씨
What should I do with this guy?
이녀석을 어떻게 할까요?
Take him to the club room.
부실로 데려와 줘
Geki! What is going on?!
게키! 대체 무슨 일이지?
Seems like this brat did something bad to Ms. Maria.
이녀석, 아무래도 마리아 씨에게 나쁜 짓을 한 것 같아
Wake up!
일어서!
Ju- just a moment, Geki senpai!
기, 기다려 주세요
게키 선배
Shut up! You are not allowed to call me  senpai!
닥쳐! 너에게 선배 소리 들을 기억 없어!
Pipe down and follow me, you brat!
순순히 따라와라, 이놈아
Uh...
저, 저기…
Good job.
수고했어
Ms. Maria., what are you...
마리아 씨, 이녀석은 대체…
An experiment begins now.
지금부터 실험할 거야
Hey, I have something to say about Kinjirou Ninomiya!
저기, 전에 말씀드린 니노미야 킨지로 말인데요
Sorry, but later.
미안하지만, 다음에 갈게
Ms. M-Maria...
마, 마리아 씨…
I told you that Maria isn't exactly a miss.
누나 하나만 여자가 아니라니까
Ms. Maria...
마리아 씨…
Uh... I have an important mission...
저기, 제겐 중요한 임무가…
Sit down.
앉아
Bu- but...
하, 하지만…
Please sit down!
앉으라고!
Okay?
네, 네…
Do you know what's on the front side of this card?
이 카드 앞면이 뭔지 알 수 있지?
Answer me.
대답해
A star.
별
Then what about this?
그럼, 이건?
Waves.
물결
Then...
그럼…
Rectangle, cross, and circle.
사각, 십자, 원
Clairvoyance...
클리어보얀스…
[clear voy ernce -본문에 설명]
Are you happy now?
이걸로 만족하셨나요?
You not only got right that a doll is inside the paper bag, but also got right what's in front of those five ESP cards.
너는 종이 봉투 안의 볏짚 인형을 맞췄을 뿐만 아니라 다섯 장의 ESP 카드를 모두 맞췄어
That's an extraordinary ability to see through!
엄청난 투시 능력이야!
An ability to see through?
투시 능력이라니요
On my planet...
우리 혹성에서는…
"My" what?!
우리 뭐라고?!
No-nothing special...
아, 아니, 그다지…
You might have more hidden abilities.
너에겐 아직 더 숨겨진 능력이 있을지도 몰라
Telepathy, foreknowledge, telekinesis, thoughtography!
텔라파시, 예지 능력
텔레키테시스, 염사!
Please stop it! I'm not a laboratory animal...
그만두세요
전 실험 동물이…
After 16 years of occult life, I can finally explain the mystery of supernatural powers!
오컬트 생활 16년 마침내 초능력의 수수께끼를 해명할 수 있어!
U-um...
저, 저기…
Who and from where exactly comes to school using a sidecar?!
어디 사는 누구냐? 사이드카 같은 걸로 등교하는 녀석!
You took the space for my bicycle!
내 자전거가 못 들어가잖아, 이놈아!
En senpai!
엔 선배~!
Please help me!
살려주세요!
Who are you?
누구냐, 너?
Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop!
기다려, 기다려
기다려 기다려!
What the hell did you do to Ms. Maria?! What happened in that room?!
아자식, 마리아 씨에게 무슨 짓을 했냐?! 그 방에서 무슨 일이 있었던 거냐?!
There must be a misunderstanding...
아니, 오, 오해예요
There is no misunderstanding!
오해 좋아하시네!
Ms. Maria is...
마리아 씨가…
Ms. Maria is crying!
마리아 씨가 울고 있었단 말이다!
That actually is...
그러니까 그건…
Answer me!
대답해라!
Your life depends on your answer!
대답에 따라선, 용서 못한다!
Just a moment, Geki.
기다려, 게키
You say that occult girl cried?
그 오컬트 소녀가 울었다고?
Interesting. Tell me more.
재밌는걸
자세히 설명해 봐라
-En! You stay out of this!
-What?!
-엔, 넌 빠져 있어
-뭐야?
It has nothing to do with you!
너하곤 관계 없어
Why you-! You're being impudent for a student from another school!
이자식, 다른 학교 학생 주제에 건방지게시리!
What did you say?!
뭐라고?!
Senpai, I'm borrowing this!
선배, 이거 빌릴게요
My bicycle! Thief!
내 자전거!
도둑이야~
-Stop!
-That brat!
-기다려라!
-저녀석!
Ryu senpai...
류 선배…
He's training to prepare for an invasion from the aliens of Sargasso...
사르갓소 우주인들의 침략에 대비해 저렇게 강인한 정신을…
That's a true member of Dagwon!
역시 다그온의 한사람이야!
Ryu senpai?
류 선배?
I have something to discuss with you!
선배에게 드릴 이야기가 있어요
Please show yourself!
모습을 보여 주세요
Ryu senpai!
류 선배~!
I'm sorry, but I have something to ask.
죄송합니다
물어볼 게 있는데요
Principal?!
교장 선생님?
You must be the transfer student.
자네는 분명 전학생인…
Yes, I'm Rai Utsumi.
네, 우츠미 라이입니다
What are you doing? Class has already begun.
무슨 일인가
수업은 벌써 시작되었다네
Sorry, but...
죄송합니다, 저기…
How do I go to the school?
학교는 어느쪽인가요?
Sorry to interrupt class. Now, you may come in.
수업 중에 미안하네
자, 들어오게
He's so cool!
잘 생겼다~
Let me introduce a transfer student.
여러분에게 전학생을 소개하겠네
I'm Utsumi Rai. Nice to meet you.
우츠미 라이입니다
잘 부탁드립니다
Wh- what the-?!
뭐, 뭐야?!
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Original Korean Subtitles by Jaebari (재바리)
Translated to English by Subdivers
Checked by Great Exkaiser103
자막 원본(번역): 재바리
수정: Subdivers
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
How this? Can you take the ball?
어떠냐, 공 뺏어봐라
That new chief is pretty nice.
이번에 온 과장,
난 왠지 싫지 않은걸
This is terrible... what happened?
너무하군
이게 무슨 일이라냐
The radar has captured a flying object.
레이더가 이동중인 비행 물체를 포착
It's heading to the Fuujin district.
후우진 구 방향이야
Got it!
알았어
Are you already cutting school?
벌써 땡땡이인가?
Sorry! An emergency situation!
죄송합니다
긴급 사태입니다!
"Super cute Rai, you're my type."
"짱 귀여운 라이 군, 내 취향이야."
I have no time for this!
이런 바쁜 때에…!
It already drank all the water in the reservoir and it's still drinking more!
저수지의 물을 남김없이 마셔버리고서 여전히 물을 계속 흡수하고 있습니다!
At this rate, the world will run out of water!
이대로 가면 전 세계가 물 부족이 된다구!
We'll finish it as a punishment!
벌로 끝장내 주마
Fire Blaster!
파이어 블래스터!
What?!
아니?!
Shadow Shuriken!
섀도우 수리검!
Drill Pulsar!
드릴 펄서!
No way!
말도 안돼!
Our attacks are going through!
공격이 관통해 버려!
It is our turn this time!
이번엔 우리 차례다!
Liner Blizzard!
라이너 블리자드!
They did it!
성공이다!
No!
아니야!
What?!
아니?!
Try Dagwon!
트라이 다그온
Thunder Rai!
선더 라이
Come here, Thunder Shuttle!
Come here, 선더 셔틀!
That's a strong guy!
엄청난 녀석이다!
How come our attacks don't work at all?!
우리 공격이 전혀 통하지 않다니…
It's soaking water too happily!
저녀석, 신나게 물을 빨아들이고 있어!
Let me try once again!
다시 한 번 갔다 올게
I'll go too!
나도 간다!
It's dangerous to do so!
섣불리 접근하면 위험합니다!
Are you telling us to shut up and watch?!
앉아서 구경이나 하란 거냐?
Wait!
기다려!
Dag Shadow, don't stop us!
다그 섀도우, 막지 마라!
Look at that.
저걸 봐라
That's...!
저건!
Will I... die?
나는 주, 죽는 건가?!
What the-?
뭐지?
I-is it saving me?
구, 구해주는 건가?
He's that guy...
그 때의…
Who are you?
넌 누구냐?
My name is Thunder Rai.
제 이름은 선더 라이
Thunder Rai?
선더 라이?
I am an alien from Planet Thunder.
혹성 쥬라이 우주인입니다
I'm sorry for what I did a while ago.
일전에는 실례했습니다
Because I didn't get an order yet, I couldn't say "hello" to you.
아직 지령을 받기 전이어서 인사도 하지 못했습니다
An order?
지령이라고?
In accordance with the order of Brave Seijin, I am formally assigned to the Earth branch, starting today.
브레이브 성인의 명령으로 오늘부터 정식으로 지구 지부에 배속되었습니다
I am a new detective of the Space Police!
우주 경찰 기구의 신참 형사입니다
Then you're a new comrade of ours?
그럼, 우리 새로운 동료?
You're my younger man?
내 후배라는 거냐?
Do the greetings later!
인사는 뒤로 미루자
What the heck is that sphere?
저 구체는 대체 뭡니까?
That's the spaceship of Sabarath Seijin, a criminal from Sargasso.
사르갓소의 죄수 사바라스 성인의 우주선입니다
Sabarath Seijin?
사바라스 성인?
Yes. It is trying to make the Earth into a desert planet by taking all the water it needs from here!
네, 녀석은 자신에게 필요한 물을 지구에서 빼앗아 동시에 지구를 물 없는 사막 혹성으로 바꾸려 하고 있습니다
Let's hurry!
서두릅시다!
Is it possible to destroy that?
녀석을 파괴할 방법은 없냐?
It might be strong for external attacks, but it might be not for internal ones...
외부에서의 공격엔 강하더라도 내부에서라면 혹시…
Leave it to me!
제게 맡겨 주세요!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체
(融合合體)
Dag Thunder!
다그 선더
다그 선더!
What?!
아니?!
Bolt Shoot!
볼트 슛!
Everyone!
여러분!
Dag Thunder!
다그 선더!
Where are you, Dag Thunder?!
어디 있나, 다그 선더?!
Dag Thunder!
다그 선더!
Fire Shovel!
파이어 셔벨!
Strength Fusion!
강력합체
(剛力合體)
Power Dagwon!
파워 다그온
Power Drill Arm!
파워 드릴 암!
Magma Blast!
마그마 블래스트!
Hang in there, Dag Thunder.
정신차려, 다그 선더
Senpai...
선배…
You aren't too bad, for a newcomer.
신참치고는 잘 하는걸
We could take down the enemy thanks to you!
네 덕분에 적을 해치울 수 있었다
That's right.
그 말대로야
Dag Thunder... who can it be?
다그 선더라…
어떤 녀석일까?
Time to reveal his identity!
드디어 녀석의 정체를 볼 수 있겠구만
He came!
왔다!
-Hey, you!
-You!
-아앗, 너!
-너!
-You're the...
-transfer student...
-넌 분명히…
-전학생!
Yes, I'm Rai Utsumi!
네, 우츠미 라이입니다
Please calm down and listen to me!
자, 잠깐 제 이야기를 들어주세요!
Shut up, you bicycle thief!
입 다물어, 이 자전거 도둑놈아!
I will never hand over Ms. Maria!
마리아 씨는 절대 못 넘겨준다!
I told you there's a misunderstanding!
그러니까 그건 오해라고 말했잖아요!
I told you there's no misunderstanding!
오해 좋아하시네라고 말했잖아!
Why did the Space Police appoint him as a detective?
저런 녀석이 저우주 경찰 기구의 형사라니…
That alien lacks everything.
하나도 못미더운 우주인이구만
I definitely want to check out his cells and tissues.
꼭 세포 조직을 조사해 보고 싶어요
My class of all classes...
하필이면 우리 반이라니…
-Stop!
-You brat!
-기다려!
-기다려라!
Please save me!
살려주세요~
The sun suddenly called me
태양이 갑작스레 나를 불러내서
taiyou ga fui ni ore wo izanau
To come to the blue sea
푸르게 비치는 바다로 만나러 갔지
aoku sukitooru umi ni ai ni kita
The ripples are coming and going
밀려왔다 돌아가는 잔물결
yosete wa kaesu sazanami
An endless melody
멈추지 않는 멜로디
tomaru koto nai MELODY
To keep that shape for eternity
그 모습을 영원히 유지할 수 있도록
sono sugata towa ni tsunagu you ni
I'll follow the fate of the dream
꿈의 행방을 뒤쫓아 갈 거야
oikakete yuku yo yume no yukue
Sparkling far away
멀리서 반짝이던
tooku kirameita
A Prism in the Wind
바람 속의 프리즘
kaze no naka no PRISM
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Preview for Next Episode
용자지령
다그온
차회예고
Those guys started to move just in time.
때마침, 녀석들이 움직이기 시작했습니다
"Those guys"?
녀석들?
They kept showing ominous activities...
계속 불안한 움직임을 보이긴 했습니다만
First, who are they?
그러니까 누구 말이냐?
Among the prisoners from Sargasso, they are the most brutal ones.
사르갓소의 죄수들 중에서도 유난히 흉악한
Their name is the Three Warugaia Brothers.
그 이름하여 와르가이아 3형제
So what are they planning?
그래서, 그 녀석들은 어떤 음모를 꾸미고 있는 거냐?
First, help me, En senpai! I'm going to be on the TV!
그런 것보다, 엔 선배! 저, TV에 나가게 되어버렸어요 하아?!
It's Maria's scheme!
마리아 씨의 음모예요
Next time on Yuusha Shirei Dagwon! The Ruler of Sargasso
다음회 용자지령 다그온
사르갓소의 지배자
Thunder Dagwon has arrived!
선더 다그온 등장!
The Ruler of Sargasso
사르갓소의 지배자